Rice Family Papers
Rice Family Papers
- Memorabilia, 1810-1957
  - Printed material
    - Rice, V[ictor] M[oreau] (Second Annual) Report of the Superintendent of Public Instruction of the State of New York, Albany: C. Van Benthuysen, 1856 (Box 5)
    - Rice, Victor M[oreau], (Special) Report of the Present State of Education in the United States and Other Countries and on Compulsory Instruction, Albany: C. Van Benthuysen, 1867 (Box 5)
    - (Rice, Victor Moreau), Spencer, P[latt] R[ogers] and Rice, Victor] M[oreau], Spencer and Rice's System of Business Penmanship, Buffalo: George Reese and Company, undated (Box 5)
    - Sheet music (Box 5)
    - Syracuse University Directory, 1912-1913; 1914-1915 (Box 5)
    - Syracuse University Handbook, 1912 (Box 5)
    - Tudor, Tasha, Thistly B, New York: Oxford University Press, 1949 (Box 5)
    - Weeks, William R., A Catechism of Scripture Doctrine, Middlebury: Francis Burnap, 1818 (Box 5)
  - Rice, Clark W[ilder], notebook of class grades, 1868-1869 (Box 5)
  - Rice, Eliza K[ingston], recipe notebook, undated (Box 5)
  - Rice, Elizabeth L[ouise], notebook on pedagogy, 1904 Feb 11 - Mar 25 (Box 5)
  - Rice, Victor M[oreau] [II?], notebook on English history, undated (Box 5)
  - Rice, Victor M[oreau] [II?], notebook on geology, undated (Box 6)
  - Sampler, Sarah K. Davis [Rice], 1840 Apr 20 (Box 6)
  - Stationery case, Mrs. Spencer V[ictor] Rice (Box 6)
  - Wallet (Box 6)
- Photographs, 1956; undated
  - Family
    - Brigham Family, See Rice, Victor Moreau, family carte-de-visite albums
    - Cemeteries, undated; 18 negatives, 26 photographs, 8 postcards (Box 6)
    - Clark Family, See Rice, Victor Moreau, family carte-de-visite albums
    - DeVine, Isabelle, undated; 1 negative, 2 photographs, and [daughter, Grace?] 1 photograph (Box 6)
      See also Rice, Helen Dorothy,1896
    - Dickinson Family, See Rice, Victor Moreau, family carte-de-visite albums
    - Dickinson, Gracie, undated; 1 photograph (Box 6)
    - Gordon, Emma Jane Kingston, and family, 1886; 1891,; 1895,; 1944,; 1954,; undated; 58 photographs (including some of China) (Box 6)
    - Hanigan, Gertrude, 1933; 1 photograph (Box 6)
    - Hosmer, Harriet, and unidentified others, 1904; undated; 2 negatives, 9 photographs (Box 6)
      See also Rice, Spencer Victor: Family group
    - Kingston, Elizabeth Hanigan, 1886; undated; 14 photographs, 1 tintype (Box 6)
    - Kingston, George Langtree (Langtry) and unidentified others, 1904; undated; 12 photographs, 2 tintypes (Box 6)
    - Kingston, George Langtree [Jr.], undated; 1 clipping (Box 6)
    - Kingston, Henry Orr and family, 1887; 1895,; undated; 9 photographs (Box 6)
    - Pets, miscellaneous, 73 negatives, 105 photographs (Box 6)
    - Residences, buildings, and landscapes, miscellaneous, 9 negatives, 14 photographs (Box 6)
    - Rice, Clark Wilder, 1870; 1874,; 1877,; undated; 69 photographs, 3 tintypes (Box 6)
    - Rice, Deacon Edmund, homestead, 26 postcards, 1 photostat (Box 6)
    - Rice, Eliza Kingston
      - and unidentified others, 1880; 1884,; 1906,; 1920,; undated; 60 negatives, 97 photographs, 6 tintypes (Box 6)
      - and unidentified others, oversize, 2 photographs (Oversize 2)
      - 1 framed photograph (Box 7)
    - Rice, Elizabeth Louise
      - 1879, 1882, 1886, 1888, undated, 24 photographs (Box 7)
      - 1895, 1900, 1904, 1908, undated, 12 negatives, 33 photographs, 3 tintypes (Box 7)
      - 2 framed photographs (Box 7)
      - and friends, 1899; 1900,; 1903,; 1904,; undated; 30 photographs, 1 tintype (Box 7)
        Some identified, including Grace Baird, Thera Bond, Kathryn Brundage, Lillian Butlin, Ella Finnegan, Edith Fosdick, Arthur Baird Hersey, Arthur Hurrell, Gertrude Kemp, Clyde Mundt, Maisa Parker, Evelyn Peake, Grace Ramsay, Carrie Roos, LaVantia Russell, George Smith, Harry Templeton, Irving Templeton, Elizabeth Tennant, Beatrice Throop
      - and friends (oversize), 5 photographs (Oversize 2)
      - and Helen Dorothy Rice, 2 photographs (Oversize 2)
    - Rice, Emily Ann, undated; 2 photographs (Box 7)
    - Rice, Gratia Louise
      - (with) Kathryn I. Hewitt and unidentified others, 1875; 1879,; 1883,; 1932,; undated; 5 negatives, 18 photographs, 12 tintypes (Box 7)
      - Residence, Lotus Mere, Cassville, New York, undated; 15 negatives, 14 photographs (Box 7)
        See also Rice, Maria Winter
    - Rice, Helen Dorothy
      - 1896, 1906, 1908, 1909, 1910, 1925, undated, 49 negatives, 138 photographs (Box 7)
      - (and) [Connecticut Children's Aid Society, New Haven, Connecticut ?], undated; 43 negatives, 7 photographs (Box 7)
      - (and) Elizabeth Louise Rice (Oversize 2)
      - (and) Homer Donald Rice, 1893; 1895,; 1898,; 1906,; undated; 3 negatives, 33 photographs (Box 7)
      - (and) Homer Donald Rice (oversize), 1 photograph (Oversize 2)
      - Senior Investigator identification (Box 7)
      - (and) Syracuse University friends (Box 8)
        Some are identified, including Helen Anderson, Mina Beach, Mildred Brouson, Frances Bryant, Lillian Cosad, Cora Cleary, Grace Decker, Lucy Disbrow, Mildred Dunn, Mildred Fisher, Grace Gilmore, Lucy James, Dorothy McConnell, Charlotte More, Bessie Partridge, Emma Plate, Gladys Porter, Mildred Sayles, Alice Smith
      - 1913, undated, 41 negatives, 92 photographs (Box 8)
      - Miscellaneous oversize, 2 photographs (Oversize 2)
    - Rice, Homer Donald
      See also Rice, Victor Moreau III
      - and unidentified others, 1919; undated; 7 negatives, 65 photographs (Box 8)
        See also Rice, Helen Dorothy
      - and unidentified others (oversize), 1919; undated; 2 photographs (Oversize 2)
      - Residences, 9 photographs (Box 8)
    - Rice, Jesse Marshall [?], undated; 2 tintypes (Box 8)
    - Rice, Lubin Waldo, undated; 6 photographs, 3 tintypes (Box 8)
    - Rice, Maria Winter, and unidentified others, 1867/8, undated; 3 negatives, 14 photographs (Box 8)
    - Rice, Sarah Whitmore, ambrotype, undated; in broken case approximately 3 1/4 x 2 3/4" with label, "Sarah Whitmore Rice, b. September 22, 1837, d. September 20, 1928" (Box 8)
    - Rice, Spencer Victor
      - including others from Lehigh University, [T. Clerc?], Professor [Coppie?], W. A. Lamberton, Professor Ringers, 1866; 1869,; 1871,; 1873,; 1877,; 1879,; 1888,; 1906,; undated; 44 photographs, 4 tintypes (Box 8)
      - (and) Clark Wilder Rice, undated; 3 tintypes (Box 8)
      - Family album, undated (Box 8)
      - Family groups, 1920; undated; negatives include interiors and exteriors; 52 negatives, 100 photographs, 2 tintypes (Box 8)
        See also Rice, Eliza Kingston
    - Rice, Spencer Victor III
      - undated, 26 negatives, 32 photographs (Box 8)
      - and Victor Moreau Rice III and Elizabeth L. Rice, 6 negatives, 2 photographs (Box 8)
    - Rice, Victor Moreau
      - Photographs, undated; 2 items (Box 8)
      - Photographs in cases, undated; 2 items (Box 8)
      - Family carte-de-visite album, with unidentified others, undated (Box 9)
      - Family carte-de-visite albums, with some identified others, undated; includes related Brigham, Clark, Dickinson, Shattuck and Valentine families; 4 albums (Box 12)
    - Rice, Victor Moreau II
      - (with) Elizabeth Louise Rice and Eliza Kingston Rice, and unidentified others, 1888; 1896,; undated; 12 photographs (Box 9)
      - (with) unidentified others, 3 negatives, 45 photographs (Box 9)
    - Rice, Victor Moreau III
      - (and) Homer Donald Rice, undated; 26 negatives, 11 photographs (Box 9)
        See also Rice, Spencer Victor III
      - (and) Homer Donald Rice (oversize), undated; 2 photographs (Oversize 2)
    - Rice, William Howard, undated; 1 tintype, 3 photographs (Box 9)
    - Shattuck Family, See Rice, Victor Moreau: family carte-de-visite albums
    - Shattuck, Ina S. and Spencer, 1881; undated; 1 photograph (Ina), 2 photographs (Spencer) (Box 9)
    - Valentine Family, See Rice, Victor Moreau: family carte-de-visite albums
    - Valentine, Gertrude, undated; 1 photograph (Box 9)
    - Valentine, Grace, undated; 1 photograph (Box 9)
    - Warner, Aurelia Winter, "Ilo", 1875; undated; 3 photographs, 1 tintype (Box 9)
  - Others
    - Grant, Ulysses S., undated; 1 photograph (Box 9)
    - Labeled miscellaneous photographs, 1864-1951; undated (Box 9)
      Photographs include:
      Herman Andrews, undated, 1 photograph
      Mrs. E. H. S. Bailey, undated, 1 photograph
      Babcock Family, 1920, and undated, 8 photographs
      Mary Jane Booth, undated, 1 photograph
      Gertrude Brown, undated, 1 photograph
      Edna M. Clark, 1934, 1 photograph
      Croghan Family, 1951, and undated, 3 photographs
      Mrs. George Dark, 1923, and undated, 4 photographs
      Julian and Richard DeGray, undated, 1 photograph
      Tho[ma]s Nelson Drew, 1947, 1 photograph
      Miss [S.?] J. Eastman, undated, 1 photograph
      Farren Family, undated, 3 photographs
      Federer, undated, 1 photograph
      Mrs. Finnegan and Lois Hills, undated, 2 photographs
      Fitzgerald Family, undated, 2 photographs
      S. C. Flint, "Little Muzzer", 1864, 1 photograph
      Mrs. Flint, undated, 7 negatives, 9 photographs
      Kate [Gollan?], undated, 1 photograph
      Reverend Albert L. Grein, undated, 1 photograph
    - Labeled miscellaneous photographs, 1895-1956; undated (Box 9)
      Howard Family, 1938, 2 photographs
      Kent Family, 1954, 1956, and undated, 4 photographs
      Dr. and Mrs. John C. Land, undated, 2 photographs
      Martha A. [W.?] Levering, 1876, 1 photograph
      Rebecca L. McDougall, 1890, 1 photograph
      Hetty McWilliam, undated, 7 negatives, 3 photographs
      Morris Family, 1895, 2 photographs
      Prester Family, 1941, and undated, 2 photographs
      Rud Family, 1921, 2 photographs
      Rogalskys Family, undated, 2 photographs
      Rogers Family, undated, 1 photograph
      Grandma Root, undated, 1 photograph
      [Caroline?] Squier, undated, 1 photograph Helen Somerville, 1898, 1 photograph
      Smith Family, undated, 1 photograph [Strasmer Family?], undated, 6 negatives
      Mrs. Taylor, undated, 1 photograph
      William C. Taylor, undated, 1 photograph
      Wright Family, undated, 1 photograph
      Janet Yule, undated, 1 photograph
    - Life motion pictures, undated; 2 photographs (Box 9)
    - Syracuse University, undated; 2 photographs (Oversize 2)
    - Unidentified ambrotype, 2 x 1 3/4 " with torn case, undated (Box 9)
    - Unidentified cabinet cards, cartes-de-visite, negatives, tintypes, 74 negatives, 13 photographs, 13 tintypes, 1 envelope (Box 9)
    - Unidentified oversized photographs, undated; 5 photograph (Oversize 2)
    - Unidentified photographs (includes one by Francis Sipprell), 96 photographs (Box 9)
    - Unidentified photographs in frames, 2 photographs (Box 9)
- Writings, 1800-1965
  - Rice, Clark Wilder
    - Composition book, 1867-1869 (Box 10)
  - Rice, Eliza M. [Kingston], 1890-1934
    - Diaries, 1890; 1923 Mar - 1924 Jul 4,; 1924 Jul 4 - 1925 Nov 30,; 1925 Dec 1 - 1927 Jun 21,; 1933 ca. Feb 22 - 1934 ca. Feb 17 (Box 10)
  - [Rice, Elizabeth Louise?]
    - Notebook (final arrangements), undated (Box 10)
  - Rice, Helen Dorothy
    - "Silk Culture", 1907 May 3 (Box 10)
    - "The Women Who Wait" poem, 1906 May 30 (Box 10)
    - (and) Homer Donald Rice, travel notebook, North Carolina trip, 1965 Sep (Box 10)
  - Rice, Homer Donald, See Rice, Helen Dorothy: (and) Homer Donald Rice, travel notebook, North Carolina trip
  - Rice, Lubin Waldo
    - Diary, 1873 (Box 10)
  - Rice, V[ictor] M[oreau]
    - "As the Twig is Bent, the Tree Inclines", 1837 Aug 4 (Box 10)
    - "Gentlemen of the Senior Class", 1840 Aug 25 (Box 10)
    - "Militia Training", 1839 May 20 (Box 10)
    - "Party Spirit", 1840 Jun 30 (Box 10)
    - "Philip", 1839 Jul (Box 10)
    - "Should the Testimony of an Atheist be Prohibited from a Court.. .", undated; 2 holograph copies (Box 10)
    - "Time in his Chariot... ", undated (Box 10)
  - Rice, William] Arthur
    - Composition book (in English and German), also includes genealogical material, undated (Box 10)
  - Winter, D[aniel]
    - "A Description of Glen Falls", undated (Box 10)
    - "Rules for Eclipses", ca. 1800-1900 (Box 10)
  - [Winter, Daniel ?]
    - "An Address in Commemoration of the Reformation in 1517", undated (Box 10)
    - "An Address to the Patechetial Society", undated (Box 10)
    - "A Descant on Happiness", undated (Box 10)
    - "A Descant on Slander", undated (Box 10)
    - "Eulogy on the Bible", undated (Box 10)
    - "Memorandum for 1815," Volume 1, no. 1-6 ( a journal), 1815 Jan 1 - Sep 30 (Box 11)
    - "Reflections on Midnight", undated (Box 11)
    - "A Review of the Wars and Commotions Since the Commencement of the American Revolution: A Poem", undated (Box 11)
    - "The Prodigal Spendthrift or Drunkard", undated (Box 11)
    - "To the Patechetical Society, Bolton", undated [but ca. 1818] (Box 11)
    - H., E. W., TLS, 1 page (Box 11)
  - Unidentified
    - Delirium, Tremens, undated (Box 11)
    - Eulogy on General George Washington, undated (Box 11)
    - [untitled], one paragraph, undated (Box 11)
- 1969 accession (M69-106:2)
  - Memorabilia, diaries, diplomas, letters, photographs, sewing samples (Dorothy Rice), tintypes, assorted other items. Unprocessed.